Guide to the Paul Ehrlich Papers SC0223
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2005-170
  - "Ecological Economics"; "Spot #1: ‘Bull in a China Shop.’ "; 1994; Media Campaigns, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - "Evolution, Education & Ecology"; "Spotlight on Kansas"; Produced and directed by Dave Kendall; With appearances by Paul Ehrlich and Jane Goodall; a production of KTWU/Channel 11;Topeka, KS;2001, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - KQED; "Paul Ehrlich and the Population Bomb"; A Production of KQED/Buffalo Gap Productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - "Consuming the Future?" Part 1 – 3; Palm & Smith Film Produktion AB, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - "Consuming the Future?" Part 4 – 6; Palm & Smith Film Produktion AB, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - KCET; "Food For Thought"; 30:00, 4/20/90; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Video tape: "Prophets and Loss" (60’); Directed and produced by Gabrielle Kelly and Nick Hart-Williams; Length: 60:00 mins.; 5/24/90 D112467; Nexus Television Ltd (Box 3)
  - DVD VIDEO: Dancing Star Foundation; Population Communication; "No Vacancy"; TRT: 90:35 min.; NTSC/Stereo; Mexico Revision; (loose iormation sheet rubber-banded) (Box 3)
  - TBS Superstation; Destination Sunday; "The Coming plague"; April 27, 1997, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - TBS Superstation; Destination Sunday; "The Coming plague"; April 27, 1997, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - KQED; "Paul Ehrlich and The Population Bomb"; A Production of KQED/Buffalo Gap Productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - The Nature of Things; Show #20 1996/97; "Paul Ehrlich and The Population Bomb"; TC: Thursday, October 31/96, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - KQED; "Paul Ehrlich and The Population Bomb"; A Production of KQED/Buffalo Gap Productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - KQED; "Paul Ehrlich and The Population Bomb"; A Production of KQED/Buffalo Gap Productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - KQED; "Paul Ehrlich and The Population Bomb"; A Production of KQED/Buffalo Gap Productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - NBC News; "Paul Erlich Series"; Audio CH 1&2 Comp; Length-58:00; 05/03/90, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - NBC News; "Paul Erlich Series"; Audio CH 1&2 Comp; Length-58:00; 05/03/90, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Econews #418; "Conversations on Population—Dr. Paul Ehrlich"; Part I 29:40; Mono c. 1987; Educational Communications, Inc., 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Environmental Series; Earthwatch; 5/3 5/4 5/5, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Paul Ehrlich; "Segments", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Show 18/INT 265-Series 8-1992, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - "Pulse of the Planet"; NPR; "Population Growth", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "Environmental Directions"'; Guest: Warner Fornos; Topic: World’s Overpopulation; Educational Communication, Inc., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - KPWR "Environmental Directions"; #637 Oct. 23, 1989 Nancy Pearlman; Dr. Paul Ehrlich—Overpopulation, Pt. III; (Rubber-banded to Pt. IV), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - KPWR "Environmental Directions"; #637 Oct. 23, 1989 Nancy Pearlman; Dr. Paul Ehrlich—Overpopulation, Pt. IV; (Rubber-banded to Pt. III), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "Reconstructing An Ecologically Damaged World" – 12/10/91; P. Ehrlich, H. Reuter, D. Saunders, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - NPR; Paul Ehrlich, 11/05/93; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - WNYC; Paul Ehrlich, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "It’s A Matter Of Survival"; Program 3; Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "Tonight Show"; March 25, 1971 (Side 1); "Frost Show"; March 27, 1971 (Side 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Society of Environmental Journalists; 6th National coerence – Oct. 17-20, 1996 – St. Louis, MO; Lunch and Debate: Doomsayers v. Naysayers—The Big Picture; Hayes/Bailey/Ehrlich/Hutton/Michaels/Raven/Schneider, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Friday, October 16, 1992; Speaker: Paul R. Ehrlich; The Commonwealth Club of California, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "It’s A Matter Of Survival"; Program 1; Canadian Broadcasting Company, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "It’s A Matter Of Survival"; Program 4; Canadian Broadcasting Company, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - NPR Interview; Ehrlich/Nielsen, August 1989; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "Science Bookshop"; ABC Radio; National; "Population Bomb", 13 July 90; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - 92AAAS-TL4 Population, Ecosystem Services, and the Human Food Supply; Paul Ehrlich; 1992 AAAS Annual Meeting; February 6-11 Chicago, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Environmental Australia; December, 1989; Side 1: "Our Finite Energy"—Paul Ehrlich, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Environmental Australia; December, 1991; Side 1: "The Economics of Fuel"—Paul Ehrlich, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Environment Show #234; 3/17/96; 25:03, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - "Desert Island Discs"; Paul Ehrlich (side B); Robin Williams (side A); ABC Australia December 1994, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Society of Environmental Journalists; 6th National coerence – Oct. 17-20, 1996 – St. Louis, MO; Lunch and Debate: Doomsayers v. Naysayers—The Big Picture; Hayes/Bailey/Ehrlich/Hutton/Michaels/Raven/Schneider, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - KPR Environmental Directions; #748 Jan. 26, 1992 Nancy Pearlman; Anne H. Ehrlich; "Population Explosion"; Educational Communications, Inc., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Dr Paul R. Ehrlich; "The Population Crisis: Where We Stand Now"; Earth Week Feature Address; University of Kansas, 28 April 1970; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 3)
  - AHE Nuclear May 91, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Dr. Paul R. Ehrlich; Interview with Michael Jackson; KABC Oct. 25 1988, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Deep Ecology for the 21st Century; "Human Reproduction: The Environmental Piledriver"; with Paul Ehrlich; copyright 1998 New Dimensions Foundation, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 3)
  - Assorted Certificates (Box 4)
  - 1 Small Photo Album (Box 4)
  - Assorted Publications (Box 4)
  - 3 hand drawn maps done by Ehrlich to illustrate his Artic travels in 1952 and 1957 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1 Framed Print, Inscribed by Artist (Box 5)
  - Assorted Certificates, Rolled (Box 5)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2006-153
  - Assorted articles, reprints, publications, clippings (up to 2004) (Box 1)
  - Notebook Fall 1961 (statistics) (Box 1)
  - 2 notebooks, n.d., on correlation and causality in biology (Box 1)
  - Correspondence file on Arizona trip, 1970-71 (Box 1)
  - Anne Ehrlich's artwork (Box 2)
  - Correspondence file, summer 1952 (Box 2)
  - Audio-visual items (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous other publications (Box 2)
  - Rolled posters and one certificate (Box 3)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2010-068
  - DVD copies of video tapes of Paul and Anne Ehrlich [list included in binder; most original tapes found in boxes 2-5], 1939-1999; 49 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - TV appearances on J. Carson Tonight Show, Today Show, Donahue Show, and others, 1976-1984. Number 2-3-4 all on 1 cassette (3 copies), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Today Show, PRE “The Birder’s Handbook” 8/1/88; Today Show Hearst, Acid Rain, 4/18/89; Channel 5 Anne Ehrlich and Dretchen Daily, 5/2/89; CNN Earth Watch, PRE Population Explosion 4/2/90. Number 5 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - PRE and C. Sagan, People are Talking; PRE and J. Gofman, Machinery of Nature; both June 1986. Number 7. Nightline, Effects of Nuclear War, PRE, C. Sagan, Teller. People Are Talking-Global Consequences of Nuclear War 11/1/1983. Number 39 [both numbers included on 1 cassette], 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - PR Ehrlich Series, NBC News, 5/3/1990. Number 8 (2 copies), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - PR Ehrlich, KCET, Food for Thought, Global Warming, circa 1990. Number 9 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - PR Ehrlich, Today SHow: Assignment Earth 1. Environmental Degradation, 2. Population, 3. Global Warming, Jan. 1990. Number 10 (2 copies), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - PR Ehlich, Today Show: EcoStories, Energy Trap, 11/27/1991. Number 11 (5 copies), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - PR Ehrlich, Earthwatch Environmental Series: Population Bomb, Endangered Species, Greenhouse Effect, May [no year noted]. Number 12 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - PR Ehrlich, Lionel Tiger, Jeffrey Schloss: Uncommon Knowledge, Hoover Institution, KTEH, Program 603, “It’s the Biology, Stupid: the Policy Implication of Sociobiology,” undated. Number 16 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - 1. Be Informed - Esprit Lectures and events, 2. Biological and Social Consequences of Nuclear Conflict, 10/10/1984. Number 18 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Without Borders 8/12/1989. Number 20 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Barraclough Carney Scare Stores: Bursting at the Seams, undated. Number 21 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - PR Ehrlich: Betrayal and Science and Reason: How Anti-Environmental Rhetoric Threatens Our Future. PARC Forum, 10/3/1996. Number 22 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Betting on the Future, PR Ehrlich, S. Schneider, J. Simon. Lateline ABC Australian Broadcasting Corp. Sydney, 11/29/1995. Number 23 (1 cassette ), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - PR Ehrlich, Conservation Biology, Tongass National Forest, Rocky Mt. Biological Laboratories, NBC News, undated. Number 24 (2 copies), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - PR Ehrlich, ”The Population Bomb,” KQED, 12/6/1995. Number 25 (6 copies), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - PR Ehrlich, Preserving the Legacy, the Delicate Balance, Part 1, Lesson #201K, [1999]. Number 26 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PR Ehrlich, Preserving the Legacy, the Delicate Balance, Part 2, Lesson #202K, 1999. Number 27 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - Advisory Council of the Institute for International Studies, First Annual Meeting, Jan. 24-25, 1991, SU, Session III Global Environment, PRE speakes at start and end of program. Number 28 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PR Ehrlich, The People Bomb, CNN Special Report, Part 1, 1992. Number 29 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PR Ehrlich, The People Bomb, CNN Special Report, Part 1I, 1992. Number 30 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PR Ehrlich, Econews Special #662, Conversations on Population at Marlborough School, circa 1989. Number 31 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - Heinz Awards, Pittsburg Introduction, 1994. Number 32 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PH Ehrlich and AH Ehrlich, Heinz Awards, Washington Presentation, 1994. Number 33 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PR Ehrlich and AH Ehrlich, “Healing the Planet,” undated. Number 34 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - AH Ehrlich, CNN World Population Report II, Feb. 1992. Number 35 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - AH Ehrlich (welcome); Charles Archambeau, Keynote Address. Cooperative Institute for Research on Environmental Sciences, undated. Number 36 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - PR Ehrlich, Today Show, Nuclear Winter, Nov. 1983? People Are Talking, PR Ehrlich and C. Amen, Nov. 1982. Number 38 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - AH Ehrlich, Moderator, 2nd Panel Discussion, Nuclear Disarmament [label reads environmental effects on nuclear winter], undated. Number 40 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 4)
  - John Birks Nuclear Winter, undated. Number 41 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - Green Peace Ecology in Action, Siberian Campaign, 1983. Number 44 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - Bound by the Wind, produced by David Brown, undated. Number 45 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - Thames Report, Television International: And On the Eighth Day, Pollution, undated. Number 46 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - Thames Report, Television International: Limits to Growth, undated. Number 47 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - The Day After - Nuclear Holocaust, Part One, 1983. Number 48. The Day After, Part Two, News Recording, 1983. Number 49 [both numbers included on 1 cassette], 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: The Nuclear Holocaust--A Scientific Forecast. Produced by NHK (Japan Broadcasting Corp.), 1984 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: KQED Nature, Animal Behavior (no PRE appearance) (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Sixty Minutes, Chemical Weapons, 1991 (no Ehrlich presence) (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 5)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Conversations on Population, Dr. Paul Ehrlich Part III and IV, circa 1989 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Panel Discussion [unable to copy] (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Econews #419 Conversations on Population, Dr. Paul Ehrlich Part II, circa 1987 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Scare Stores Programme One Population: Bursting at the Seams, 20 Nov. 1997 (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Econews #400 Conversations on Population, Dr. Paul Ehrlich, circa 1988 [bad tape] (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Econews #418 Conversations on Population, Dr. Paul Ehrlich Part I, circa 1987 [bad tape] (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no DVD copy in box 1]: Ehrlich, Sunday morning, Dec. 17, 1989 [bad tape] (1 cassette), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 6)
  - [no copy in box 1]: Lateline: “Rethinking Darwin” 8/10/98 (2 copies), 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 6)
  - [no copy in box 1]: Foreign and Domestic Policy: Its Impact on Every American’s Life, Wed. July 15, 2009. Speaker: Paul Ehrlich “The Dominant Animal: Human Evolution and the Environment”, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 6)
  - [no copy in box 1]: Earth Days, a Robert Stone film with Paul Ehrlich, screener of finished film, 3/16/2009, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 6)
  - [no digital copy in box 1]: WBEZ - Odyssey, 10/25/2000, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 6)
  - PRE, Diversity and the Steady State, Mitchell Prize Submission, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - PRE, The Food from the Sea Myth: the Natural History of a Red Herring, presented to the Commonwealth Club of California, April 21, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Research proposal: A survey of the biting flies of the vicinity of Kotzebue, Alaska, March 20, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter: The Jaybug, Dept. of Entomology, University of Kansas, March 1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Crafoord Prize [photo, CD disc, card] 2007 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Volvo Environmental Prize, The 20 First Years by Tor Kihlman, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous items (ZPG brochure, clipping, program, letter) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Chinese translation of PRE book WILD SOLUTIONS (Box 7, Folder 8)